Zachary Stoebner

Research Overview

My research spans **image & signal processing**, **deep learning**, and **machine perception** to solve challenging problems in autonomous systems. Generally, my interests are in AI/ML & neuroscience, intelligent systems & robotics, and optimization & control.

Education

University of Texas at Austin

Austin, TX

PHD IN ELECTRICAL & COMPUTER ENGINEERING

August 2022

- Advisor: Prof. Jon Tamir
- Focus: Computational sensing and imaging

Vanderbilt University

Nashville, TN

August 2021 - May 2022

- MS IN COMPUTER SCIENCE
- Advisor: Prof. Ipek Oguz
 Thesis: A deep learning-enabled automatic segmentation system for surgical endoscopy

Vanderbilt University

Nashville, TN

August 2017 - May 2021

- BS with Honors in Computer Science & Neuroscience
- Minor in Applied Mathematics
- · Advisor: Prof. Ipek Oguz
- Research: ML for brain MRI: (1) GAN-based harmonization and (2) cortical shape analysis using linear-mixed models

Select Publications

IN PROGRESS

Ahmadi, Mohsen, Kevin Leach, Ryan Dougherty, **Zachary A. Stoebner**, Michael Sandborn, Stephanie Forrest, and Westley Weimer. "Mimosa: Reducing malware analysis overhead with coverings." arXiv preprint arXiv:2101.07328 (2021). Submitting to Oakland 2022.

Contribution: deep multilabel classification of malware binaries + simulating scalability based on classifier performance [GitHub]

CONFERENCE

Zachary A. Stoebner, Daiwei Lu, Seok Hee Hong, Nicholas L. Kavoussi, and Ipek Oguz, "Segmentation of kidney stones in endoscopic video feeds", Proc. SPIE 12032, Medical Imaging 2022: Image Processing, 120323G (4 April 2022). [SPIE] [arXiv]

IN REVIEW

S. A. Setia, **Z. A. Stoebner**, C. Floyd, D. Lu, I. Oguz, and N. L. Kavoussi, "Computer vision enabled segmentation of kidney stones during ureteroscopy and laser lithotripsy," Endourology, 2022.

Zachary A. Stoebner, Kilian Hett, Ilwoo Lyu, Hans Johnson, Jane S. Paulsen, Jeffrey Long, Ipek Oguz, "Comprehensive shape analysis of the cortex in Huntington's disease", Human Brain Mapping, 2022.

Select Honors & Awards

2022 Cockrell Engineering Fellowship, University of Texas at Austin

\$ 36,000

Select Presentations

POSTERS

* presenting author

Zachary A. Stoebner*, Daiwei Lu, Seok Hee Hong, Nicholas L. Kavoussi, and Ipek Oguz. "Segmentation of kidney stones in endoscopic video feeds". Vanderbilt Institute of Surgery & Engineering Symposium. 2021. Nashville, TN.

Nicholas L. Kavoussi*, **Zachary A. Stoebner**, Daiwei Lu, Ipek Oguz. "Automated Method of Tracking and Segmenting Kidney Stones During Ureteroscopy Using Computer Vision Techniques". Engineering & Urology Society Meeting. 2021. Las Vegas, NV.

TALKS & LECTURES

Fall 2021 ML for Course and Research Projects, CS 4262 - Foundations of ML

Vanderbilt

Teaching Experience _____

ASSISTANT

Spring 2022	Projects in ML, CS 3892	Vanderbilt
Fall 2021	Artificial Intelligence, CS 4260	Vanderbilt
Spring 2021	Deep Learning, CS 3891	Vanderbilt
Fall 2020	Operating Systems, CS 3281	Vanderbilt
Spring 2020	Discrete Structures, CS 2212	Vanderbilt
Fall 2019	Discrete Structures, CS 2212	Vanderbilt

Service & Outreach _____

2021-2022	Community Outreach Chair, Out in Engineering	Vanderbilt
2021-2022	Peer Reviewer, Section Leader, & Graduate Mentor, Undergraduate Research Journal	Vanderbilt
2019-2021	Mentor & VP of Communications, Engineering Design Studio	Vanderbilt

Skills_____

Programming: Python, C++, C, MATLAB, R, JavaScript, ŁTEX

Engineering: soldering, CAD, 3D printing

Language: English (native), Portuguese (fluent), Spanish (advanced), French (basic)

Other: kū & tanka poet, nature photographer, lifter & runner